hi folks this is Matt again I am going
大家好，我又是马特
to tell you a little bit about the
告诉你一些有关
Shapley value now which is one of the
现在的Shapley值是
most prominent ways of dividing up the
最主要的划分方式
value of a society the productive value
社会价值生产价值
of some set of individuals among its
在其中的一些个人
members and you know the the basic idea
成员，你知道基本的想法
in coalition or cooperative games in
在联盟或合作游戏中
terms of trying to figure out allocating
试图弄清楚分配的条款
values is having some notion of what the
价值观对什么
right way to do things is and we might
正确的做法是，我们可能
say even in quotes say what's the fair
说甚至引号说什么公平
way of a coalition to divide up its its
联盟划分其方式的方式
payoff it's obviously going to depend on
收益显然取决于
the way that we define fairness and the
我们定义公平的方式以及
literature has basically then taken ways
文学基本上已经采取了方式
taking axioms as the primary way of
以公理为主要方式
expressing the properties of what the
表达什么的属性
desired properties are of rules for
所需的属性是规则
dividing up things so so what we're
划分事物，所以我们
going to do is then have some set of
然后要做的是
axioms or properties that we want to
我们想要的公理或属性
satisfy and then see what that gives us
满意，然后看看这给了我们
the Shapley value is based on lloyd
Shapley值基于劳埃德
Shapley's idea that members should
Shapley的想法，成员应该
basically be receiving things which are
基本上是收到东西
proportional to their marginal
与他们的边际成比例
contributions okay so so basically you
捐款还可以，所以基本上你
look at what what is a person add when
看一个人什么时候加什么
we add them to a group and they should
我们将它们添加到组中，他们应该
be getting something that reflects their
得到一些反映他们的东西
added value to the society okay so
为社会增值，好吧
what's the tricky part about this let's
这是什么棘手的部分，让我们
just take a quick example and that'll
举个简单的例子，
give us an idea of why we have to be
让我们知道为什么我们必须
careful in doing this so let's suppose
这样做要小心，让我们假设
that everybody in together in a society
在一个社会中每个人在一起
can generate one but that if we're
可以产生一个，但是如果我们
missing any member of society we get
缺少我们得到的社会成员
zero so this is say of a committee and
零，这就是说一个委员会，
the committee all has to be present in
委员会所有人都必须出席
order for it to do anything so if it's
命令它做任何事情，如果它是
missing any of its members it can't just
缺少任何成员都不能
make it decided to decide on anything so
使它决定要做出任何决定
in this situation what do we so we've
在这种情况下，我们该怎么做
got you know V of n is equal to 1 V of s
知道n的V等于s的1 V
is 0 if we're looking at any s that's
如果我们正在查看的是，则为0
smaller than n so in this situation
小于n所以在这种情况下
what's true then the marginal
什么才是真正的边际
contribution if we take any individual
如果我们承担任何个人的贡献
out of this group
在这个群体之外
they're marginal contribution is one
他们的边际贡献是一
right so everybody is essential for
对，所以每个人都是必不可少的
generating this one so everybody's
产生这个，所以每个人的
marginal contribution to the the society
对社会的边际贡献
without them is one and in this
没有他们是一个，在这个
situation we can't pay everybody what
情况我们不能付大家什么
they're responsible for in terms of
他们负责
leading ultimately to the to the grand
最终通往盛大
coalition so we're going to have to
联盟，所以我们将不得不
think about some way of weighting
考虑某种加权方式
contributions in order to come up with a
为了拿出一个
reasonable thing and obviously for this
合理的事情，显然
particular rule it would be reasonable
特定规则是合理的
to add up things by 1 over n so
把n加1
everybody gets one end of the
每个人都结束了
contribution but in rules we're in
贡献，但是按照规则
situations where there's might be some
可能会有一些情况
asymmetric asymmetries in terms of who
关于谁的不对称不对称
contributes which value we're going to
贡献我们将要获得的价值
have to think fairly carefully about how
必须相当仔细地考虑如何
this should be weighted okay so
应该加权好吧
Shapley's axioms are going to give us a
Shapley的公理将给我们一个
handle on this so let's take a look at
处理这个，让我们看一下
those so the first idea is a very simple
这些，所以第一个想法很简单
one and one which pretty much any rule
一个和一个几乎任何规则
that you would would think of in these
您会在这些中想到的
settings is going to satisfy so if we
设置将满足，所以如果我们
think of two different members of
想起两个不同的成员
society say I and J if they contribute
社会说我和J如果他们贡献
the same thing to every possible
一切皆有可能
coalition in which they could be a
他们可能成为一个联盟
member they're completely
成员，他们是完全
interchangeable so that if we're looking
可互换，以便我们在寻找
at some coalition that has neither I nor
在一些既没有我也没有联盟的联盟中
J in it if we had I to that coalition we
如果我们让我加入那个联盟，
get exactly the same value as we get
得到与我们得到的完全相同的值
when we add J to that coalition if
当我们将J添加到该联盟时，如果
they're interchangeable then they should
他们是可互换的，那么他们应该
be getting out the same allocation of
摆脱相同的分配
value so if SCI is the way that we're
价值，因此，如果SCI是我们的方式
dividing up the value from some
将价值从一些中除掉
coalitional game then we should be
联盟游戏，那么我们应该
giving the same thing to I as J when
当我给我和J相同的东西时
they're completely interchangeable okay
他们是完全可以互换的
this is a fairly uncontroversial axiom
这是一个毫无争议的公理
it really captures a basic notion of
它确实捕捉了一个基本概念
fairness that if this you know if
公平地说，如果你知道
individuals are completely equivalent
个人是完全等同的
they should get equivalent payments okay
他们应该获得等额付款
next axiom dummy players so I'm sure
下一位公理虚拟玩家，所以我敢肯定
that that everyone has had some
每个人都有一些
experiences with people like this what's
这样的人的经验是什么
the idea
这个主意
there's a situation where you you add a
在某些情况下，您添加了
person I to a coalition and they they
我一个联盟的人，他们他们
add absolutely nothing so no matter what
绝对不添加任何东西
as we look at if we add AI
当我们查看是否添加AI时
to particular us we get the same value
特别是我们，我们获得了相同的价值
as this situation with without that
没有这种情况
individual so basically the person is
个人，所以基本上这个人是
completely worthless no matter what
无论如何，一文不值
coalition we're looking at so the idea
我们正在寻找联盟，所以这个主意
is then the axiom is if an individual is
那么公理是如果一个人是
a dummy player then we give them nothing
一个假人然后我们什么都不给
now you know this is on one hand it's a
现在你知道这是一方面
fairly reasonable axiom if somebody's
如果有人的话，这是相当合理的公理
contributed absolutely nothing there's
绝对没有贡献
no reason they should get anything on
没有理由他们应该得到任何东西
the other hand this depends very much on
另一方面，这在很大程度上取决于
the perspective you're taking so if
您所采用的视角，如果
we're thinking about a society it could
我们正在考虑一个可以
be that that eye contributes nothing
那只眼睛什么也没做
because of reasons beyond eyes control
由于无法控制的原因
so something happened they had an
所以发生了一些事
accident or um for some particular
意外或嗯
reason they are unable to function
他们无法运作的原因
Society might still want to allocate
社会可能仍想分配
something to those individuals so it
给那些人一些东西
really depends on what the time
真的取决于什么时间
perspective is whether we're thinking
视角是我们是否在思考
about social insurance and so forth but
关于社会保险等等
but nonetheless it's a fairly intuitive
但是还是很直观的
axiom and is going to be a fairly
公理，将是一个相当
powerful one in and what it delivers
强大的功能之一及其提供的功能
next one is additive 'ti this one is one
下一个是添加剂'ti这是一个
which you might think of more about the
您可能会想到更多关于
process of allocating value so let's
分配价值的过程，所以让我们
suppose that we can think about looking
假设我们可以考虑寻找
at a cooperative game or coalitional
在合作游戏或联盟中
game and we can it's one that separates
游戏，我们可以分开
very nicely into two different parts so
非常好地分为两个不同的部分
we can think of it as as you've got one
我们可以将其视为您拥有的
cooperative game you've got another one
合作游戏，你还有另一个
and then we think of what do you get
然后我们想到您会得到什么
when you sum these two things together
当您将这两件事加在一起时
and the idea is that if we're looking at
想法是，如果我们正在研究
two different cooperative games and then
两个不同的合作游戏，然后
we think about what would happen if you
我们考虑如果您
were trying to allocate something when
试图分配一些东西的时候
you sum them up you should get the same
你总结他们，你应该得到相同的
thing from allocating one allocating
分配一个东西
according to the second and then adding
根据第二，然后添加
those two things up okay so the idea
这两件事都好，所以这个主意
here is if we're looking at a
如果我们正在看一个
cooperative game where the value for
合作游戏的价值所在
veni Coalition is just what it gets
veni联盟就是它所得到的
under the first game Plus what it gets
在第一个游戏下加上它会得到什么
under the second game then the way that
在第二局下，
we allocate values should be how we
我们分配价值应该是我们
allocated things under the first game
在第一局比赛中分配了东西
plus how we allocated things under the
加上我们如何根据
second game so you know this is a
第二场比赛，所以你知道这是一个
fairly obvious in terms of what it means
在含义上相当明显
mathematically in terms of how you
在数学上就你如何
interpret this and what the story is for
解释这以及故事的目的
why you might desire to have to satisfy
为什么您可能想要满足
an axiom like this that's a little
这样的公理有点
harder you could think of this as a
很难将其视为
story for saying you know maybe society
说你可能知道社会的故事
one day produces according to v1 and the
一天根据v1产生
next day according to v2 and if what it
第二天根据v2，如果有的话
produces the second day doesn't depend
产生第二天不依赖
on want to produce the first day then we
想要生产第一天，然后我们
should we should be able to allocate the
我们是否应该能够分配
the fruits of the production in the
生产中的成果
first day and then allocate again on the
第一天，然后在
second day and and those things since
第二天，以及那些事情以来
they don't interact at all we should be
他们根本不互动，我们应该
able to do that separately and what an
能够分别做到这一点，
individual gets is just the sum of those
个人得到的只是那些的总和
two things so you can you know think of
两件事让你知道
a fairly logical story for this kind of
对于这种情况，一个合理的故事
axiom okay so what do we get from these
公理好吧，我们从这些中学到什么
three axioms the Shapley value and let's
Shapley值的三个公理，让我们
have a look at exactly how you define
看看您如何定义
the Shapley value so the value the
Shapley值，所以值
Shapley value is going to be marginal
Shapley的价值将是微不足道的
calculations what is an individual I add
计算我添加的个人是什么
two coalition's that don't have I when
当我没有两个联盟
we add so we've got a coalition with I
我们加上，所以我们与我结盟
in it coalition without I we we then
在没有我的联盟中我们
take a peek at how much that generates
看看产生了多少
and then what we're going to be doing is
然后我们要做的是
waiting that by different possible ways
以不同的方式等待
in which we could have come up with this
我们本来可以想到的
marginal calculation and then dividing
边际计算然后除
through by all the possible ways that we
通过所有可能的方式
could have done this okay so we'll make
可以做到这一点，所以我们将
sure we average over all these things so
确保我们对所有这些事情取平均
that everything sums up to the full
一切都总结为全部
value okay that's the the Shapley value
值就是Shapley值
we're going to dissect this in more
我们将在更多内容中对此进行剖析
detail in a moment
稍后详细
and what's the theorem the theorem is
定理是什么定理是
that if we look at a coalitional game or
如果我们看一个联盟游戏或
a cooperative game there's a unique way
合作游戏有一种独特的方式
that divides the full payoff of the
划分了全部收益
grand coalition so if we're making sure
大联盟，所以如果我们确定
we're dividing everything up that
我们正在把一切都分开
satisfies symmetry dummy and additive
满足对称假人和加性
'ti so if you put those three axioms
所以如果你把这三个公理
together there's only one way to do it
在一起只有一种方法
and that way is the Shapley value so
那就是Shapley的价值，所以
there's a unique wave which does satisfy
有一个独特的波浪确实满足
these and it's the Shapley value so
这些就是Shapley的价值，所以
that's a pretty powerful theorem
这是一个非常强大的定理
there's a fairly elegant proof to this
有一个相当优雅的证明
it's a fairly intuitive we're not going
这是非常直观的，我们不会
to go through that in detail but we'll
详细介绍一下，但我们会
go through some explanations of this you
通过一些解释你
can find the proof fairly easily in a
可以很容易地在
number of different places there's
那里不同地方的数量
actually a nice book by Osborn and
实际上是奥斯本写的一本好书，
Rubinstein for instance which is free
例如鲁宾斯坦是免费的
online which has a proof of this but
在线有一个证明，但
there's a number of places where you can
有很多地方可以
find this ok let's have a peek at the
找到这个好吧，让我们来看看
actual value in terms of what how this
实际价值如何
breaks down and then we'll look at some
分解，然后我们来看一些
examples so what individual is giving is
例子，所以个人给的是
according to this formula looks a little
根据这个公式看起来有点
daunting but the intuitions are fairly
令人生畏，但直觉相当
simple so let's think we're thinking of
很简单，让我们认为我们正在考虑
marginal contributions how are they
边际贡献如何
coming about so what we're going to do
即将到来，所以我们要做的是
is we're going to think of all the
是我们要考虑所有的
different possible ways we could build
我们可能建立的不同方式
society up so for instance we could be
社会发展起来，例如我们可以
building society up by first adding
通过首先加入来建立社会
person 1 then adding person se 3 then
人1然后添加人se 3然后
adding person two right so we could that
再加上两个人，这样我们就可以
that would be one order in which we
那将是我们的一个顺序
could build a society up we could also
可以建立一个社会，我们也可以
have built it up by first adding person
通过首先添加人来建立它
2 then adding person 3 then any person 1
2然后加人3然后再加人1
right so there's a whole series of
对，所以有一系列的
different ways if we had a three person
如果我们有三个人的话
society that we could go about building
我们可以建设的社会
these things up and in each according to
这些东西，并根据
each one of these orders will have
这些订单中的每一个都会有
different different marginal
不同的不同的边际
contributions along the way so here
一路走来，所以这里
first person one contributes something
第一人称视角
then person three adds their production
然后第三个人添加他们的作品
then person two adds their production
然后第二个人添加他们的作品
and so forth so we end up with these
等等，所以我们最终得到了这些
these different contributions and that's
这些不同的贡献，那就是
what this is going to capture so what
这将要捕获什么
we're doing is we're looking at these
我们正在做的是我们正在看这些
different sequences and the first part
不同的顺序和第一部分
we're doing is calculating as we went
我们正在做的是计算
along the sequence what did I add when
按照顺序我在什么时候添加了什么
they were added next we weight this by
接下来添加它们，我们将其加权
the different possible ways that we
我们可能采取的不同方式
could have built up the coalition's
本来可以建立联盟的
before I was added then we also weight
在添加我之前，我们也要称重
this by
这个由
the different orders different ways we
不同的订单，不同的方式
could add the individuals who haven't
可以添加没有的人
been added yet after I has been added
被添加后，我被添加了
right so there's a a number of
对，所以有一些
individuals - the number that are
个人-人数
already in s - I so that's the number of
已经在s-我就是
ways the people that are still left
留下来的人的方式
effect take that - the factorial gives
效果取-阶乘给出
us how many different orders we can
我们可以有多少不同的订单
still add people in so we waited by that
仍然增加了人，所以我们等待
and then we're summing over all possible
然后我们总结所有可能的
combination of coalition's that are
联盟的组合是
there before I and then we're dividing
在我之前，然后我们分开
through by the total number of different
通过总数不同
orderings we could have over people in a
我们可能会超过一个人的订单
society okay so that's the Shapley value
社会还可以，这就是Shapley的价值
and in terms of understanding this again
并再次理解这一点
what we could think of in terms of the
我们可以想到的
the ways we divide up a society we can
我们分裂社会的方式
think of you know adding person 1 first
想起你知道先加人1
then 1 2 1 2 3 we could have added 1
那么1 2 1 2 3我们可以加1
first then 3 1 2 3 we could have added 2
首先，然后3 1 2 3我们可以添加2
first then 1 then 3 - first then 3 3
首先然后1然后3-首先然后3 3
first then 1 3 first then 2 to 3 and so
首先然后1 3首先然后2到3等等
forth so we could have done this in a
来吧，所以我们可以在一个
whole series of different orders so
整个系列的顺序不同
there's six of these right six different
这些正确的六个中有六个
orders and so for instance if we want to
订单等，例如，如果我们想
figure out what person 1 adds when we
弄清楚人1在我们加入什么
add them in the first case this is V 1
在第一种情况下将其添加为V 1
second case this is V 1 third case what
第二种情况是V 1第三种情况是什么
are they adding they're adding V 1 2
他们正在添加V 1 2
minus V of 2 that was already there
减去2的V
third case they're getting V of 1 2 3
第三种情况他们得到1 2 3的V
minus V of 2 3 that's the fourth case
减去2的V就是第四种情况
the fifth case we're getting V of 1 3
第五种情况我们得到1 3的V
minus V of 3 and so forth right so we've
减去3的V，以此类推，所以我们已经
got here V of 1 2 3 minus V of 2 3 okay
到这里1 2 3的V减去2 3的V好
that's the Shapley value so each one of
那就是Shapley的价值，所以每个
these things is getting weighted by 1/6
这些东西的权重是1/6
here this
在这里
turns out then to to get a total weight
事实证明然后得到总重量
of one-third again here we're going to
三分之一再次在这里，我们要
get a weight of 1/3 and then these two
得到1/3的权重，然后这两个
are each getting a weight of one six two
每个人的体重都是一六二
each right so that gives us the total
每个权利，这样就给了我们总数
value of the Shapley value and that
Shapley值的值，以及
tells us what person one should be
告诉我们应该是谁
getting and this is setting you know
得到，这是你知道的设置
let's take a look at a simple simpler
让我们看一个简单的
example just with two individuals and
例如两个人
try and figure out exactly what the
尝试找出到底是什么
Shapley value gets so these are two
Shapley值得到，所以这是两个
people they form a partnership so person
他们建立伙伴关系的人
1 alone was generating production of one
一个人就产生了一个
person two was generating a production
第二个人正在生产
of two they say wow let's get together
他们说两分之三，哇，让我们聚在一起
and form a partnership we can do better
建立伙伴关系，我们可以做得更好
than we can separately they generate a
比我们可以分别产生的
total value of four so this is a nicely
总价值为四，所以这是一个不错的选择
super additive we're getting a higher
超级添加剂，我们越来越高
value when we've got the two together
当我们将两者结合在一起时的价值
and now with a sort of at the end they
现在在某种程度上，他们
try and say okay well how should we
试着说好吧，我们应该如何
divide the four among among them well in
将其中的四个很好地划分
this case we could have added one first
在这种情况下，我们可以先添加一个
and then one come up with one two
然后一个拿出一两个
the other possibility is we get to first
另一种可能性是我们首先
and then one two right so there's only
然后一二对，所以只有
two different ways we could have built
我们本可以建立两种不同的方式
society up so person one in the first if
如果第一人称社会
we're trying to figure out what to give
我们正在努力弄清楚该给什么
person one out of this here they would
从这里一个人，他们会
get v1 right which is one here they
得到正确的v1，这里是他们
would get a V 1 2 minus V of 2 the
将得到V 1 2减去V 2
marginal contribution they added if
他们添加的边际贡献如果
they're at it second this is the
他们在第二，这是
marginal contribution if they were at it
如果他们在边际贡献
first
第一
what's this value this value is two and
这个值是多少，这个值是二，
each one of these gets a weight
这些中的每一个都具有重量
ultimately of one-half because we've got
最终只有一半，因为我们有
two of these things so we're adding a
其中两件事，所以我们要添加一个
half of one a half of 2 we get 1 point 5
一分之二的一半我们得到1分5
is equal to fee of 1 you can go through
等于您可以通过的手续费1
you can check that 2 point 5 then is
您可以检查2点5就是
going to be equal to fee of 2 so here
等于2的费用，所以这里
what do we end up with the Shapley value
我们最终会得到Shapley值
gives us that if these are the
给我们，如果这些是
contributions that people are making
人们所做的贡献
you're going to end up with 1.5 as the
您最终将得到1.5作为
right amount to give to person 1 and 2.5
给人1和2.5的正确金额
to give to person - okay so they're each
给人-好吧，他们每个人
in this case getting some value that
在这种情况下，获得一些价值
depends on the
取决于
so it's it's taking into account what
所以这是考虑到了什么
these values are in trying to divide the
这些价值是在试图划分
four so they don't just say okay let's
四，所以他们不只是说好，让我们
just split the four or 5050 they're
只需将四个或5050分开
doing a different calculation than that
做不同的计算
and comes out at one point five and two
并在五点和二点出来
point five in this case okay so what
在这种情况下要点五点好
about the Shapley value it allocates the
关于Shapley值，它分配
value of a group according to marginal
边际价值
calculations it's captured by some very
计算它被一些非常捕获
simple logic and and axioms and what you
简单的逻辑和公理以及您
could do is you can think of other
可以做的就是你可以想到其他
axioms you can think of other ways other
公理，您可以想到其他方式
fairness ideas or other kinds of things
公平观念或其他类型的事物
that you desire your your rule to
你希望自己的规则
satisfy and that's going to come up and
满足，这将会出现，
make different kinds of predictions and
做出不同的预测
we'll take a look at the core next which
接下来我们看一下核心
is another it uses a different kind of
是另一种使用不同种类的
logic than the Shapley value for making
比Shapley值更具逻辑性
predictions about how a society should
关于社会应该如何的预测
divide up as values
分成价值